难道你不愿意孤注一掷  真刀真枪地干出点名堂
Wouldn't you rather give it all at once to something real?
本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
我们要偷什么
What would we be stealing?
一整个帝国星区的季度工资
The quarterly payroll for an entire Imperial sector.
《安多》前情提要
如果是我  我也会这样做
If I was them, this is how I'd do it.
■
本字幕由                        联合分享
迪幻字幕组
星球大战中文网
尽量分散
I'd spread it out.
迪幻字幕组   www.deefun.com
星球大战中文网   www.starwarschina.com
打一枪换一个地方
Never climb the same fence twice.
比克丝
Bix!
■
时间轴： WaitinZ
是谁干的
Who did this?
蒂姆
Timm!
所以你完全不抱希望是吗
So you think it's hopeless, do you?
■
翻译： Disney+官方字幕（姚望）
自由  独立
Freedom? Independence?
我们就得逆来顺受  感激涕零
We should just submit and be thankful?
■
注释： Homura
我像感激涕零的样子吗
Do I look thankful to you?
-下士  -听候命令
- Corporal. - At your service.
■
后期： WaitinZ
入列
Fall in.
向右转
Turn.
齐步走
With me.
答应我  别出事
Tell me you'll be all right.
放心吧
I'll be fine.
去吧
Go.
开始搬
Let's go!
这是怎么回事
What is going on here?
我被困住了
I'm pinned down!
不
No!
抓紧了
Hang on!
我猜现在  你的前途一片暗淡吧
My assumption is, you have no prospect for the future.
我去联系哈尔洛叔叔
I'm calling Uncle Harlo.
好歹也是亲戚一场
I'm calling in the family favor.
你猜里面有多少钱
You wanna guess how much is in there?
差不多一人四千万
Forty million a piece, give or take.
-所以你不是反抗军  -我是反抗者  不过
- So no rebellion for you? - Oh, I'm a rebel. It's just, uh...
我反的是所有人
me against everybody else.
他想独吞拿笔钱  把你们都扔在这里
He wanted to take the money and leave you here.
-他不会那么做  -我只拿走我那份
- He wouldn't do that. - I'm taking my cut.
我把事办完了
I did my job.
我想有个人也许能帮我
I found someone I think can help me.
我们已经岌岌可危了
We're vulnerable enough.
我们需要资金  而不是更多人手
We need funding, not more people.
别跟我说什么岌岌可危
Don't lecture me on vulnerability.
没人比我冒的风险更大
No one's more at risk than I am.
星球大战
安多
第一季第七集
希里尔
Syril?
Syril!
你就打算穿成这样
Is that what you're wearing?
就这样吧
It would seem so.
你以为标准局会欣赏
What makes you believe the Bureau of Standards
有个性的员工吗
is in the market for individuals?
只是件棕色衣服
It's a brown suit.
可这是面试
It's your interview.
你是不是想和我一起去
Perhaps, you would like to come along.
哈尔洛叔叔给你安排的  咱们可不能怠慢
Uncle Harlo's influence is not a thing to be trifled with.
我怎么怠慢了
How am I trifling?
他这可是帮了我们一个大忙
He's done us a tremendous favor.
你得记住  今天你不仅仅是代表自己
You need to remember you're not just representing yourself today.
只是件棕色衣服
It's a brown suit.
衣领
The collar.
怎么了
What about it?
太高了
It's high.
你把它加高了
You've had it raised.
我定制的
I had it tailored.
从细节能看出一切  希里尔
Everything says something, Syril.
我想让你明白  你总是不听
I've tried to make you understand that, you've resisted.
你从我的衣领能看出什么
What is it that you hear my collar saying?
“看看我”
"Look at me.
“我对自己没信心”
"I don't believe in myself.
“我迫切需要认可”
"I am desperate for approval."
我们刚刚收到令人震惊的报告
We have distressing reports are reaching us
阿尔达尼的帝国军械库
that a terror attack and robbery
遭到恐怖袭击和抢劫
have taken place at the Imperial Armory on Aldhani,
据报道有多人死亡
with multiple fatalities reported.
怎么回事
What happened?
-暴徒  -发布了封锁令
- Rabble. - ...a Blockade Order was issued...
他们袭击了当地驻军
They attacked a garrison.
他们会后悔的
They'll regret it.
现场官员仍在评估损失
...officials on the scene are still assessing the loss
并搜寻共谋者
and searching for the conspirators.
昨晚袭击阿尔达尼的罪犯
The criminals responsible for last night's atrocity on Aldhani
自认为打得帝国措手不及
think they've taken the Empire by surprise.
我们早有准备
We know better.
他们将在震惊中发现
We know the real shock will be
我们随时可以积极回应
when they discover how ready and eager we are to respond,
今天上午我们在这里
to be prepared, to be here this morning
需要讨论的唯一问题
and know that the only question we need to answer
就是打击手段的强硬程度
is how tight to close our fist.
所以我们要制定计划
This is why we plan.
要在和平时期居安思危
This is why we work so hard when we're at peace.
所以我们招募人员如此严格  要求如此之高
This is why we recruit so carefully and demand so much.
从今天起  帝国全境将采取以下措施
The following measures will be adopted Empire-wide as of today.
任何窝藏叛军的地区都将加征税款
A tribute tax equal to five times the amount stolen from Aldhani
金额相当于阿尔达尼劫案的五倍
will be levied on any sector harboring partisan activity.
我们将昭告天下  没人能盗窃帝国财产
We will make it clear that no one steals from the Empire.
任何利用地方习俗  传统节日或民族文化
The use of any local custom, festival, or tradition
掩护叛军行动的地区
as cover for rebel activity
将被帝国永久撤销民俗许可
will trigger permanent revocation of Imperial tolerance.
昨晚我觐见了帕尔帕廷皇帝
I spoke with Emperor Palpatine last night,
他向我保证  帝安局将全面主导相关工作
and he's assured me that the ISB will be taking the lead going forward.
在座各位
No one in this room
都将有权调用陆海军的任何资源
should have trouble accessing Army or Naval resources in future.
皇帝将召开议会紧急会议
The Emperor will be convening an emergency session of the Senate
提出一揽子法案和修正案
to propose a legislation package of bills and amendments
全面放开我们的权限  进行监视  搜查和扣押
that will free our hands in all matters of surveillance, search, and seizure.
我们将在今天晚些时候援引公共秩序重判指令
We will be invoking the Public Order Resentencing Directive later today.
公序重判令
P-O-R-D.
任何犯罪行为  包括对帝国产生间接损害
Any criminal act, with even indirect effect on the Empire,
今后都将被列为一级犯罪
will henceforth be branded a Class One Offense.
所有刑期将立即重新评估
All prison sentences are immediately re-evaluated.
所有未缴罚款和征费都将全额支付
All outstanding fines and levies are to be paid in full.
-我已向皇帝保证  -你不太高兴
- I have assured the Emperor... - You're not pleased.
这种做法正中他们下怀
We're playing straight into their hands.
-他们是谁  -叛军
- Whose hands? - The rebels.
这正是他们想要的
This is exactly what they want.
把阿尔达尼事件仅仅当作一次抢劫
We're treating what happened at Aldhani like a robbery.
那您怎么看
What would you call it?
这是一次宣言
An announcement.
初步调查显示  损失超过八千万信用点
Preliminary investigation puts the loss at over eighty million credits.
驻防基地所有军事人员都已被替换
All military personnel at the garrison have been replaced
正在接受帝安局审查
and are being interrogated by ISB.
帝安局证实逃跑飞船上的跟踪装置
ISB confirms the tracking devices
在到达超空间之前就已遭到破坏
in the escape craft were disabled prior to it reaching hyperspace.
134名阿尔达尼居民已被拘留
134 Aldhani residents have been taken into custody
他们涉嫌教唆恐怖分子
under suspicion of abetting the terrorists.
蒙·莫思马
Mon Mothma.
她怎么来了
Without warning?
收起你的笑容
Wipe the smile off your face.
我应该提前通知你
I should've called.
我们正在去议会的路上  突然想起会路过这里
We're on our way to the Senate, I realized we'd be passing by.
-等我一会  -好的
- I'll be right back. - Ma'am.
佩林说他喜欢  不知道是不是真心话
Perrin likes it, I'm just not sure he loves it.
我还是换另外那个吧
I think I might want the other one.
你干的吗
Was this you?
什么意思
What do you mean?
阿尔达尼的驻防基地
The garrison. Aldhani.
那是真的
Ah! Is it true?
克蕾娅刚和我说
Kleya was just...
我一直担心你会做这种事
I've been worried you might do something like this.
我真希望是我
How I wish I had.
先来看看吧
Let's have a look.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
-说明你不够努力  -别这样跟我说话
- Well, you'll have to try harder. - Don't you dare talk to me like that.
革命是需要代价的
Revolutions are expensive.
我告诉过你  我已经竭尽全力了
I told you, I'm doing everything I can.
你的“全力”似乎只是
Your "everything" seemed to be all about
找一个救星来取用你的家庭资金
bringing in a savior to access your family funds.
是你干的  对吗
It was you, wasn't it?
我向你解释过找外人的风险  但你似乎不以为然
I explained to you the risk of new faces, but you seemed to know better.
你知道你做了什么吗
You realize what you've done?
我以为你是来说会议的事
I thought you were here to tell me about the meeting.
是今晚
It's tonight.
他们可能会改期
They may reschedule.
一开始我就警告过你
I warned you when we started.
-你说我们在建立一个网络  -我当时是怎么说的
- You told me we were building a network. - What were my words?
这完全是另一回事
This is something else entirely.
“一旦开始就不可能回头”
"Turning back will be impossible."
你知道事情会怎么发展
You knew where this was going.
你心里很清楚
You've always known.
谁会制造武器却只当摆设
Has anyone ever made a weapon that wasn't used?
网络已经建成  开始运作
The network's been built. It's up.
不进则退
It grows or it dies.
我们已经等得够久了
We've waited long enough.
你明白这会导致什么后果吗
You realize what you've set in motion?
是时候面对后果了
It was time for that as well.
-帕尔帕廷现在不会犹豫了  -没错
- Palpatine won't hesitate now. - Exactly!
正如我们所愿
We need it.
我们需要恐惧
We need the fear.
需要他们反应过度
We need them to overreact.
你说什么疯话
You can't be serious.
帝国在慢慢扼住我们的喉咙  而我们在渐渐麻木
The Empire has been choking us so slowly, we're starting not to notice.
是时候逼他们下狠手了
The time has come to force their hand.
人民会受苦
People will suffer.
这是计划的一部分
That's the plan.
你并不生我的气
You're not angry at me.
我只是大声说出你已经知道的事情
I'm just saying out loud what you already know.
接下来将不会有任何规则
There will be no rules going forward.
如果你狠不下心
If you're not willing to risk your conscience,
那就投降放弃吧
then surrender and be done with it.
我们要竭尽所能搞到每一笔钱
We need every credit we can get our hands on.
记得告诉我会议进展
Let me know how the meeting goes.
恐怕今天早上这两样我都不想要
I'm afraid I won't be taking either of these pieces this morning.
我这里很快会到一批新货
I'll have some new things coming in very, very soon.
我一定会来看看
I'll be sure to come by.
随时为您效劳  议员
Always at your service, Senator.
随时为您效劳
Always at your service.
我希望她靠得住
I hope she's worth it.
只能走着瞧了  对不对
Well, we'll see, won't we?
我们不能躲一辈子
We can't hide forever.
人们都以为我们在开玩笑  但这是真的
People all think we're kidding when we say it, but it's true.
标准局没有小事
There are no small jobs at the Bureau Of Standards.
我和你叔叔谈过了
I spoke with your uncle.
表面上看  有些部门似乎更有吸引力
Some sectors might naturally appear more exciting from the outside.
重量和测量部看起来好像更有活力
Weights and Gauges may seem a more vibrant arena
冗余或检验部似乎有些沉闷  但走一走
than Redundancy or Verification, but walk the floor,
随便找个终身雇员聊聊  你会感到惊讶的
talk to any lifetime employee, you'll be surprised.
我明白
I'm sure.
莫拉纳一号
Morlana One.
是的
Yes, uh...
有一个叛军凶手逍遥法外
There's a rebel murderer running free
因为企业当局腐败松懈
because of corruption and laxity in the corporate authority.
我一心维护法律却受到惩罚
I was punished for trying to uphold the law.
我只想尽责  维护公共安全
Do my job. Maintain public safety.
两人遇害
Two men dead.
是我同事
Co-workers.
我相信违法必究
I believe that we have laws for a reason.
我希望恢复名誉  消除履历污点
I fully intend to clear my name and have my record expunged.
为什么不从现在开始呢
Why don't we start that process now?
入职前稍微编辑一下你的档案  对大家都好
Probably best for everyone to just edit this a bit before signing you in.
我相信你叔叔会同意的
I'm sure your uncle would approve.
重新开始  对吗
Fresh start, eh?
全新的开端
New beginnings.
燃料纯度部正好会有一个空缺
We just happen to have an immediate opening in Fuel Purity.
我不希望你错过这个机会
I'd hate to see you miss your chance.
出口向右前往议会层
Exit right for the Senate level.
出口向左前往商业区和中心区层
Exit left for the downtown, midtown level.
4-9向量6
Four-nine vector six.
LUH-341
L-U-H-three-four-one.
安全许可代码
Security clearance code...
-菜品很不错  -非常精致
- The food is superb. - It's quite exquisite...
稍息  资料员
At ease, Attendant.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
女士  长官
Ma'am. Sir.
你的制服
Your tunic.
对不起  长官  女士
Sorry, sir. Ma'am.
抱歉
Sorry.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
费尔佐尼斯
Felzonis.
资料员  费尔佐尼斯
Attendant Felzonis.
我需要过去两年的跨区整合数据
Hmm. I need a Multi-Sector Data Blend going back two years.
调取帝国海军基地和修理设施的数据池
The survey pool is Imperial Naval bases and repair facilities.
我要一份记录  包含所有遗失的航空设备
I want a record of all missing avionics,
通讯器  导航和瞄准设备
comm, navigation, and targeting equipment.
哪个星系
For which star system?
所有星系
All star systems.
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
这份报告属于绝对机密  副本只送到我的办公室
I'll need this report kept confidential and a copy sent exclusively to my office.
你能胜任这种保密级别的工作吗
Can I rely on you for that level of discretion?
绝对可以
Absolutely.
是的  我能做到
Yes. Can do.
向我保证
Will do.
我保证
很好  开始吧
Right. Get on with it.
注：帝国歼星舰(Imperial Star Destroyer)，银河帝国最著名的象征之一
他怎么没来
Where is he?
我根本不该来这里
I shouldn't even be here.
我们俩都不该来
Neither of us should.
钱很安全
The money's safe.
我们知道
We know.
已经转移了  你的工作很出色
It's been moved already. You've done exceptional work.
我们更担心那艘拖船
It's the trawler that we're more worried about.
埋了  找不到了
It's buried. Gone for good.
-你确定  -确定
- You're sure? - Yes.
他看了你的消息
He read your message.
我以为他会来
I really thought he'd be here.
每次牺牲都不相同
Every loss is different.
每个人都一样
Every one's the same.
我亲自招募了塔拉敏
I recruited Taramyn myself.
内米克  戈恩  他们会被铭记
Nemik, Gorn, they'll all be remembered.
仅此而已
That's it?
他本来就怀疑斯基恩
He had doubts about Skeen.
至少现在不用担心了
It's one less thing to worry about.
有辛塔的消息吗
Have you heard from Cinta?
她在执行她的任务
She's doing what she was told.
接收和发送消息同样危险
Receiving messages is just as dangerous as sending them.
你应该记住这一点
You should keep that in mind.
还有件事没解决
We have a loose end.
卡西安·安多  也就是克莱姆
Cassian Andor, who you know as Clem.
你得找到他
You need to find him.
找他
Find him?
他见过卢森  目前下落不明
We can't have him walking around with Luthen in his head.
你是指杀了他
You mean kill him.
这就是革命的真面目  薇尔
This is what revolution looks like, Vel.
我们会把他的资料发给你
We'll send you what we have on him.
谁在那里
Who's there?
我听见了
I hear you!
等  等一下
Just, just hold on!
-卡西安  -快进来
Cassian. - Oh! Get in here.
咱家什么时候开始锁门了
Since when do we lock the door?
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
你不能留下  卡斯  这里不安全
You can't stay here, Cass. It's not safe.
冲锋队来了
There is t-t-troopers now.
-这么快  -对  第二天就来了
- That was fast. - Yeah, they came the next day.
赶走了普莫  霸占了酒店
Kicked out Pre-Mor, took over the hotel.
费里克斯正式被帝国接管了
Ferrix is under Imperial authority.
你不该回来
You shouldn't be here.
我是被人告发的
Someone turned me in.
你还不知道
You don't know?
知道什么
Know what?
-是蒂姆  -什么
T-T-Timm. - What?
蒂姆·卡尔洛告发了你
Timm Karlo turned you in.
怪他也没用  他死了
No point in stewing over it, he's dead now.
企业兵追捕你的时候杀了他
The Corpos killed him when they were coming after you.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know all this?
大家都知道
Everyone knows it.
-比克丝早就知道  -不
- Bix knew about it? - No.
她想来警告你  蒂姆想拦住她
She was coming to warn you, and Timm was trying to stop her,
或者想抓她  我不确定
or to catch her, I don't know.
说什么的都有
I've... I've heard both.
但你不能待在这里  卡斯
But you can't be here, Cass.
帝国的人要长期驻扎
The Imperials are here to stay.
这次他们不会走了
They're not going away this time.
一切都完了
It's all come undone.
我们不用担心这个
We won't have to worry about that.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们要离开这里
We're getting out of here.
远走高飞
We're leaving.
去哪里
To go where?
想去哪里都行
Anywhere we want.
我走运了
I got lucky.
我有钱了
I scored.
我的信用点足够我们去任何地方
I've got enough credits to get us anywhere.
我们一起走
We're gonna clear out.
远离这个鬼地方
Leave this mess behind.
什么时候走
When d-d-do we go?
-今晚就走  -今晚
- We go tonight. - Tonight?
是啊  不行吗
Yeah, why not?
就我们三个  还需要什么
What do we need to take but the three of us?
离开这个又冷又湿的地方
Huh? Get out of the cold and damp.
找个温暖舒服的地方
Find somewhere warm and easy.
只要你一句话
I can make it happen.
现在一切都变了  妈妈
It's all gonna be different now, Ma.
怎么了
What's wrong?
这实在太突然了
Just such a lot to take in.
没人知道我在这里
No one knows I'm here.
我们简单收拾些东西  一走了之
We take what we can carry, and we disappear.
这可是天大的事  我太累了
It's just such a big idea, you know, I... I get so tired.
我不知道说什么了
You surprised me.
我怎么这么着急  大晚上的
What am I thinking? It's... It's late.
对  你需要休息
Yeah, yeah. You... You gotta rest.
我去找下比克丝  我们明天一早就走
I'll check up on Bix, and we'll pull out first thing in the morning.
-好吗  -明天一早
All right? - F-F-First thing.
就这么办
Let's do that.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉  没有准备正餐
Sorry we're not having dinner.
这次待多久
How long are you staying?
我明天回钱德里拉
I'm back to Chandrila tomorrow.
我一整年没回去了
I haven't been home all year.
你没错过什么大事
You haven't missed much.
错过了你呀
I've missed you.
我去的时候  好像你总是不在
You always seem to be away when I'm there.
我可没那么难约  蒙
I'm not that hard to find, Mon.
你可是议员
Not for a Senator.
说得对
You're right.
-我这个朋友不够意思  -我不是那个意思
- I've been a poor friend. - No, that's not what I meant.
生活让我们各奔东西
Life takes us where it will.
这么多年来  你成就斐然
You've become all this. All these years.
我们都今非昔比了
We're both a long way from where we started.
我变了很多吗
Have I changed so much?
-我们都得适应变化  -有那么糟吗
- We've all had to adapt. - Is it that bad?
我可不敢想象住在这里  蒙
I just can't imagine living here, Mon.
这种生活
Like this.
在科洛桑
Coruscant.
无处可逃
No escape.
我体验了这里的生活  你每天的应酬
Just this glimpse of what it's like here, what you have to do.
有时候是有点挑战性
It can be challenging.
你应对得游刃有余
You carry it gracefully.
我能信任你吗  泰
Can I trust you, Tay?
看在我们昔日的情谊上  想听听我的真实想法吗
Can I call back our old kinship and share some truth with you?
母亲
Mother.
莉达
Leida.
-记得我女儿吗  -当然
- Do you remember my daughter? - Of course.
这位是泰·科尔马  妈妈的老朋友
This is Tay Kolma, one of my oldest friends.
您好
How do you do?
你们以前见过
You've met before.
在科尔马银行  你在家乡见过阿德琳和玛萨
Bank Of Kolma? You know Adrine and Marsa from back home.
是我姐妹
My sisters.
记不清了
Um, I'm not sure.
时间太久了  你都长这么大了
It's been a long time, and you've certainly grown up.
大家都这么说
So everyone says.
我是银行家
Typical banker.
说不出什么新鲜话
No one pays me to be original.
父亲说我想走要经得你的同意
Oh. Father said I needed to ask you if I may be excused.
好的
Yes.
你可以走了
You're excused.
很高兴见到你
Lovely seeing you again.
是的
Uh, yes.
玩得开心  妈妈
Have fun, Mother.
这是另一种挑战
Another part of the challenge.
正是叛逆的年纪
It's a difficult age.
我斟酌再三  才决定和你聊聊  泰
I've spent a great deal of time thinking about this conversation, Tay.
我想告诉你一件事
I want to tell you something
这件事全银河系只有三个人知道
that only three people in the galaxy know about.
为什么选择告诉我
Why would you want to do that?
因为我需要你的帮助
Because I need your help.
我希望我能相信你
And I'm hoping I can trust you.
是私人的还是政治的
Is this personal or political?
是政治
Political.
-那你最好考虑清楚  -为什么
- Then I'd suggest you hesitate. - Why?
注：右侧有一个礼仪机器人(protocol droid)
就像我说的  我们都变了
Like I said, we've both changed.
我对帝国的态度不仅仅是厌倦
I've done more than grow weary of the Empire.
恐怕我的政治观点对你来说有点激进
I'm afraid you'd find my politics a bit strong for your taste.
你的世界与帝国有千丝万缕的联系
Your world is inescapably linked to the Empire.
你身边一直围绕着这些人
You're with these people all the time.
我不知道你是否意识到
I'm not sure you're aware how far afield
有些人的政治忠诚已经偏离了正轨
some of us have taken our political allegiances these days.
抱歉  我可能喝了太多佩林的大使馆佳酿
Sorry, I think I've had too much of Perrin's Embassy punch.
喝吧
Drink up.
多喝点  泰  保持微笑
Drink up, Tay, and keep smiling
假装我们在愉快地谈论童年时光
as if we're having a happy chat about childhood days.
我不太明白你的意思
I'm not sure I understand.
你不懂
No, you don't.
你对我的看法和人们对我的评价  都很一致  不是吗
What you see, what people say about me, it's a clear picture, isn't it?
我是位彬彬有礼  时而优柔寡断的议员
I'm a polite, sometimes-indecisive Senator
她屡战屡败  试图保护分离主义改良派
who spends her days fighting and failing to protect Separatist do-gooders
阻止帝国权力过度扩张
and battle Empire overreach.
令人厌烦  正如你之前所说的
An irritation, as you so harshly put it.
-我惹你生气了  -不  你让我放心了
- I've made you angry, I... - No, no. You've set me free.
我想了一整天  能否向你倾诉
I've been wondering all day how I could be sure of confiding in you.
我不知道我们在谈论什么
I don't know what we're talking about.
那是个假象
It's a lie.
人们自以为了解的蒙·莫思马  是个假象
The Mon Mothma people think they know, it's a lie.
是投影
It's a projection.
是幌子
It's a front.
微笑
Smile.
我从帕尔帕廷身上学到的
I've learned from Palpatine.
我露出手里的石头  你就不会注意到脖子上的刀
I show you the stone in my hand, you miss the knife at your throat.
你把我说糊涂了  蒙
Where is this going, Mon?
总理大臣在我的分离派联合会议中  安插了亲信
The Grand Vizier has infiltrated my Separatist Coalition meetings.
我的司机是帝安局特务  汇报我的秘密人道主义项目
My driver is an ISB plant and reports on my secret humanitarian programs.
他们在监视我  这正合我意
They know they watch me, and I want that,
如果所有人都认为  我只是讨人厌
because as long as everyone thinks I'm an irritation,
他们就会忽视我真正在做的事
there's a good chance they'll miss what I'm really doing.
你到底在做什么
What are you really doing?
筹集资金
Raising money.
我要动用我的家庭帐户
I need to access my family accounts.
不久前
Until recently,
我还能随意动用我的家庭财产
I was able to dip in and out of my family fortune without concern.
现在情况变了
That's changed.
我需要帮助
I need help.
筹钱干什么
Raising money for what?
我在筹备一个钱德里拉慈善拓展项目
I'm forming a Chandrilan charitable outreach program.
我会请你担任主席
I'll ask you to be chairman.
需要你来科洛桑进行访问
It will involve visits here to Coruscant.
就像是又一件善意和无用的麻烦事
It will appear to be another of my benevolent and useless irritations.
我考虑过替代人选
I've explored the alternatives.
你是我的最佳选择
You're my best shot.
你还没回答我的问题
You haven't answered my question.
我不会回答
And I won't.
你也最好不要知道
You're better off not knowing.
否则你会发现我的政治观点  对你来说有点激进
Or perhaps, you'd find my politics a bit strong for your taste.
佩林要过来了
Perrin's on his way over.
他对此一无所知  他不值得信任
He knows none of this. He's not to be trusted.
微笑
Smile.
你们在这里啊
There you are.
在回忆学生时代
Reminiscing, are we? School days?
这么容易被你看透了
Are we that predictable?
-马上要开同学会了  -别提醒我
- There's a reunion coming up. - Oh, don't remind me.
她假装不在乎  但我们都了解她  对吧
She pretends not to care, but we both know better, don't we?
她一直都这样
It was ever thus.
我可以借用她一会吗  有几位客人要招呼一下
May I steal her back? There's a few guests that require special handling.
当然
Of course.
下次再聊
To be continued.
嘿
Hey.
卡斯
Cass?
嘿
Hey.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
还记得你爸那次抓到我翻墙吗
Remember when your father caught me climbing over that wall?
这里是你最不该来的地方
This is the last place you should be.
我想那是他当时的原话
I think those were his exact words.
这里不安全
It's not safe here.
蒂姆
Timm?
我猜他以为我们又在一起了
I guess he thought you and I were back together.
他为什么会这样想
Why would he think that?
我比你更惊讶
You can't be as surprised as I was.
你这是怎么了
What happened to you?
我自己不小心摔的
I ran into a wall, like I do.
你得赶紧走  卡斯
You can't be here, Cass.
冲锋队抓不住我
Troopers won't catch me.
放心吧
Not here.
他们不需要
They won't have to.
有人会告发你
You'll be turned in.
-谁  -谁
- By who? - By who?
任何人
By anyone.
人家觉得这些都怪你
People blame you for what happened.
怪我
Blame me?
你杀了两个企业兵  回家躲着
You killed two Corpos and came home to hide.
害整个镇子陷入危险
Put the entire town at risk.
-现在到处是帝国兵  -都怪蒂姆多嘴
- Now there's Imperials on the street. - If Timm had kept his mouth shut.
怪这个  怪那个  怪你  怪我  怪蒂姆
If this, if that. If you, if me, if Timm.
我们刚刚完成你安排的交易
We were doing a deal you...
你坑蒙拐骗  欠一屁股债  一走了之
You scam, you borrow, you lie, you disappear.
你的神经病男友想害死我  我却成了恶人
Your crazy boyfriend tries to get me killed, and I'm the villain?
你得离开这里  越远越好
You need to get as far away from here as you can.
嚯
Wow.
我会的
I will.
这就走
I am.
你再也不用为我烦心了
You won't have to worry about me anymore.
我需要知道那个人的情况
I need to know about the other guy.
那个买家  他是谁
The buyer, who is he?
-我不知道  -你在骗我
- I don't know. - You're lying.
我没有
I'm not.
是帕克介绍的  但他也不清楚
Paak introduced us, but swears he doesn't know either.
我只有通讯器  呼叫对方  等回复
I have a comm. I call. I wait.
有时他们会回应
Sometimes they respond.
他知道我的一切  为什么
He knew all about me. How?
我不知道
I... I don't know.
你说得对  他确实知道
And you're right, he did know.
他知道企业兵在抓你  不是我说的
He knew that the Corpos were on you. But not from me.
如果你再联系上他  告诉他我履行了约定
You ever talk to him again, tell him I held up my end of the deal,
他必须忘记我
and he needs to forget about me.
其他人也一样
And that goes for everybody.
这个我熟
I've done it before.
一万两千信用点
12,000 credits.
我欠的都在这里了
That's everything I owe.
赞  努尔基  布拉索  迪玛
Xan, Nurchi, Brasso, Deema.
一万二应该够了
Twelve should cover it.
小心点  卡斯
Be careful, Cass.
你也是
You too.
这和我们无关  卡斯
This is not our fight, Cass.
别担心  他们不会待着不走的
Don't worry. They won't be here long.
他们会抗着那愚蠢的旗帜离开
They're just gonna raise their silly flag and fly away.
注：前共和国大军的克隆人士兵，帝国时期克隆人部队逐步改组为冲锋队
共和国万岁
Long live the Republic!
解放费里克斯
Free Ferrix!
待在这里  不要走动
Don't move. Stay here.
大家冷静一点
Hey, guys! Calm down!
-这样只会让事情更糟  -立定
- You're only making things worse! - Halt!
向后转
Turn!
举枪
Ready arms!
玛尔瓦
M-M-Maarva.
他回来了
He's b-b-back.
我正准备去找你
I was coming to find you.
我回来了
Here I am.
你们没收拾行李
You haven't done much packing.
她说我们不能走
She says we can't go.
毕  安静
Bee. Quiet.
你怎么了
What is this?
我不走了
I'm not going.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我要留下
I'm staying.
可这里不安全
But it's... it's not safe.
我知道
I know all that.
我不能留在这里
I can't be here.
你自己说了  “一切都完了”
You said it yourself, "It's all come undone."
在里克斯路有个帝国兵营
There's an Imperial barracks on Rix Road.
祝他们好运
Good luck to them.
-你愿意活在阴影下  -哪里都一样
- You wanna live under that? - It's happening everywhere.
我们会找到一个还没被毁掉的地方
Well, we'll find a place they haven't ruined yet.
我已经找到了
I'm already there.
就在我的脑袋里
That place is in my head.
无论他们造多少兵营  他们永远找不到我
They can build as many barracks as they like, they'll never find me.
这里还有什么可留恋的
What's left to keep you here?
反抗
The Rebellion.
什么
What?
费里克斯躲藏得够久了
Ferrix has been hiding long enough.
现在你要挑战帝国了
So now you're taking on the Empire?
想笑就笑吧
Laugh if you want to.
我哪笑了  这太离谱了
Who's laughing? This is madness.
不  才不是
No, it's not.
早该这样  可能注定会失败  我太老了  已经不在乎了
It's overdue, and probably doomed, and I'm too old, and I don't care anymore.
13年来  每次走在里克斯路上
For 13 years, every time I walk down Rix Road,
我都在广场前掉头走开
I turn off before I get to the square.
我绕远路
I take the long way around
这样我就不用想起克莱姆被吊在那里
so I don't have to think about Clem hanging there.
昨天  我听说阿尔达尼被袭击了
Then yesterday, I heard about this attack at Aldhani.
你听说了吗
Have you heard about this?
怎么了
What about it?
毕给我播了新闻
Well, Bee played me the news.
你知道我说的事吗
Do you know what I'm talking about?
知道  阿尔达尼的驻防基地
Yeah, yeah, the garrison at Aldhani.
我听了新闻  穿上我最好的外套
I heard that, I put on my best coat,
我面带微笑地走过了广场
and I walked across the square with a smile on my face.
如果有英雄敢对抗整个帝国驻防基地
If there are heroes brave enough to take on a whole Imperial garrison,
我也有足够的勇气在这里坚持到底
I'm brave enough to stick it out here.
我不指望你能理解
I... I don't expect you to understand.
阿尔达尼只是场抢劫
Aldhani was just a robbery.
人们站起来了
People are standing up.
是啊  然后送了命
Yeah, and getting killed for it.
但我们必须做点什么
But there's work that will need doing.
是吗  做什么
Yeah? What is that?
不管需要做什么
Whatever it takes.
我一直在躺着等死
I've been lying around waiting to die long enough.
你赢不了他们  玛尔瓦
You can't beat them, Maarva.
逃跑了肯定赢不了
Not if I run away.
你有自己的路  卡斯  我并没有责备你
You have a different path, Cass, and I am not judging you.
你经历了那么多
Everything you've been through,
甚至一开始你就被夺走了一切
everything that was taken away from you before you even started?
带上你所有的钱  去过平静的生活吧
Take all the money you've found and go and find some peace.
我不可能平静
I won't have peace.
我会一直担心你
I'll be worried about you all the time.
那就是爱
That's just love.
你对它无能为力
Nothing you can do about that.
我爱你胜过一切
I've never loved anything the way I love you,
为你担心也胜过一切  但这一次
and I've never fretted on anything more, but this time...
你不能留下  而我不能离开
you can't stay, and I can't go.
-我可以说话了吗  -不行
- C-C-Can I speak now? - No!
你懂了就说句话
Tell me you understand.
我不懂
I don't.
你会的  你会明白的
You will. You'll see.
还有一件事
And just one more thing... Just...
别再找你妹妹了
Stop searching for your sister.
那是幻想
It's a fantasy.
克纳里星没有幸存者
There were no survivors on Kenari.
那里发生的事不是你的责任
What happened there was not your responsibility.
你那时还小
You were a child.
放手吧
Let it go.
我会回来的
I'm coming back.
你当然会
Of course you are.
另一种分析是通过比较拘留人数
The alternative analysis is that by comparing the detention numbers
和突击检查的频率
to the frequency of surprise inspections
发现我们的港口巡逻部队分配不足
we're under-allocating our harbor patrol units.
有三种理论  扬先生
So, three theories, Mr. Jung?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
三种可能性解释了
Three possible explanations
为什么你没跟上邻近星区的步伐
for why you have failed to keep pace with your neighboring sectors.
-您说得对  -我说得对
- That's correct. - I'm correct?
感谢你的认可
Your approval is heartening.
期待您多指教  长官
Your guidance would be welcome, sir.
很好  全面审核所有通往曼特尔兵站的超空间通道
Very well, let's have a full audit of all hyperspace lanes leading to Ord Mantell
明天这个时候把报告交给我
on my desk by this time tomorrow.
遵命
As you wish.
-布莱文先生  -长官
- Mr. Blevin. - Sir.
今天早上我感觉你似乎很急迫的样子
I sense something eager in you this morning.
我没看错吧
Am I mistaken?
不  长官  不得不说  您说得对
No, sir. And at risk of repetition, you are correct.
是好消息吗
Good news, is it?
恐怕不是
I'm afraid not.
我想对一位同事提出指控
I wish to lodge a charge against a fellow supervisor.
说
Proceed.
有人违反辖区条例
I believe our Sector Protocols,
无视帝安局行为准则
as described in the ISB Code Of Conduct,
她就是米罗监督官  其越权行为
are being violated by Supervisor Meero, and that this overreach,
早已受到过谴责  此举危及帝国安全
for which she was previously reprimanded, risks compromising Imperial safety
我对此无法保持沉默
to a degree that silence is no longer possible.
现在说这个合适吗
You think this forum appropriate?
合适
I do.
这是严重的指控
It's a serious charge.
相信您能理解事情的紧迫性
I believe you'll share my sense of urgency.
米罗监督官
Supervisor Meero,
你愿意公开自证你的操守吗
do you mind having your integrity ventilated in public?
当然  长官
No, sir.
布莱文监督官显然认为我的行为
Supervisor Blevin obviously finds my conduct a more interesting subject
比改进帝国综合安全更值得研究
than the advancement of Integrated Imperial Security.
他这么卖力  我很想听听他的见解
He's put a lot into it, I'm curious to hear his insights.
关于费里克斯  对吗
This is Ferrix, is it not?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
你的辖区
Your sector.
发现了一部罕见的海军装备
There was an unusual piece of Naval equipment recovered.
米罗想要你的犯罪报告
Meero wanted your crime reports.
您认定她的请求不合流程
You determined her request was out of order
-并且违反了指挥链  -这不准确
- and in violation of the chain of command. - That's not accurate.
您建议我用数据佐证我的怀疑
You advised me to reinforce my suspicions with data
并在今后的工作中更加小心
and to be careful in my work going forward.
小心
Careful?
这就是你的辩护吗  你很“小心”
Is that your defense? You've been "careful"?
我很好奇在座有多少人
I'd be curious how many people at this table
会认为你很“小心”  因为你访问我们辖区的数据
will think it "careful" that you've found a way to access our sector data
却没有提交任何申请
without ever filing a request.
是真的吗  黛德拉
Is that true, Dedra?
是的
Yes.
我依据《帝国紧急法》  在阿尔达尼事件后
I used the Imperial Emergency Act in the wake of Aldhani
收集了多个辖区的数据  并未经过官方审批
to gather data across multiple sectors without official sanction.
但这是个错误的问题
But that is the wrong question.
我想知道在座是否有人相信  叛军在规划行动时
I'd like to know if anyone here believes the Rebellion plans its actions
会遵守我们人为划定的辖区边界
around the artificially constructed boundaries of our sectors.
这些辖区是帕塔加兹少校设立的
Major Partagaz created those sectors.
为了便于管理  而非让人把玩
As organizing principles, not personal playthings.
你认为叛军会在乎我们在星图上画的线吗
Do you think the rebels care about the lines we draw on maps?
你认为我的规划不再符合实际需求了吗
You think the relevance of my work has been supplanted?
体制不改变  就会灭亡
Systems either change or die.
长官
Sir.
你的论点呢
Thesis, please.
叛军正有目的  有组织地
There is a focused, organized rebel effort
窃取严格管控的帝国军事组件
to acquire highly-restricted Imperial military components.
你的证据呢
Your evidence?
通过调取原始的辖区犯罪报告
By accessing unfiltered Sector Crime Reports
我能证明我们被盗的机密设备
I can now prove a link between the theft of our most secret equipment
被分发给全银河系的叛军组织
and its distribution to rebel groups across the galaxy.
你可以提供可靠  可验证的数据吗
This is hard, verifiable data you are prepared to present?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我相信布莱文监督官知道我已准备好一份文件
I believe Supervisor Blevin is aware I have a documented file ready to go.
我相信他今天早上的指控
I believe his accusations here this morning
更多是出于自我保护  而非所谓紧迫性
have more to do with self-preservation than any sense of urgency.
还有比不规矩的情报人员更紧迫的问题吗
What's more urgent than a renegade intelligence officer?
如果在座的每个人都像你一样不守规矩会怎样
Imagine if everyone in this room played as loose with the rules as you.
好建议  布莱文
Excellent suggestion, Blevin.
我在想  如果在座的每个人
I'm wondering where we'd be right now if everyone here
都像米罗监督官一样努力会怎样
showed the same endeavor as Supervisor Meero.
我得考虑一下
I'll have to think about that.
我决定暂时把莫拉纳星区分配给米罗监督官
For the moment, I'm reassigning the Morlana sector to Supervisor Meero.
费里克斯是她重点关注的星球
Ferrix is of great interest to her
它显然让你过度分心了
and has clearly become a distraction for you.
我认为没有紧迫问题
I see no urgent problem, but, as always,
但我一向欣赏这种发人深省的思想交流
I salute the provocative exchange of ideas.
格兰迪监督官  你要加快进度
Supervisor Grandi, you will accelerate your schedule.
扬  我期待明天你关于曼特尔兵站的报告
Jung, I will expect your report on Ord Mantell tomorrow.
注：曼特尔兵站最早出自《帝国反击战》中的一句台词，是银河系的旅游胜地之一
感谢大家的热烈讨论
Thank you all for the lively session.
黛德拉  你到我这里来一下
Dedra, if you'd walk with me a moment.
干得不错
Well-played.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
你要当心了
Watch your back.
尼亚莫斯
基夫
Keef.
Keef?
我马上就好
I'll be out in a minute.
你在干什么
What're you doing?
洗个澡
Washing up.
出去走走
I'm gonna take a walk.
我们得买点东西
Well, we need stuff.
阿尔基商店在海滩上
Arkie's up the beach.
应该开门了
He'll be open.
我本来想走另一条路
I was planning to go the other way.
阿尔基有新口味
Mmm, Arkie has the new flavors.
买几瓶皮佐斯
And we need Peezos.
别忘了皮佐斯
Don't forget the Peezos.
皮佐斯喝完了
We ran out of Peezos?
皮佐斯和悦诺格酒
Peezos and Revnog.
那种绿绿的
The greenie green ones.
绿色的悦诺格酒
The greenie Revnog.
你也爱喝的
You liked it, too.
基夫  你在听么
Keef? Are you listening?
快跑
Go! Go! Run!
快
Go, go, go, go!
嘿  你  站住
Hey, you! Stop!
站住
Hold it!
不许动
Freeze!
注：这些是ID9搜索机器人(ID9 seeker droid)，出自《义军崛起》
你来这里干什么
What are you doing?
注：海岸防御冲锋队(coastal defender stormtrooper)
专门驻守热带地区的士兵，出自《侠盗一号》
怎么了
Excuse me?
你鬼鬼祟祟地在干什么
You keep looking around.
我只想看看到底是怎么回事
Just trying to figure out what's going on.
你参与了吗
You a part of it?
参与什么
Part of what?
别装傻
Don't play dumb.
不  我正要去商店
No, I'm on my way to the store.
你站着别动
Back up.
站在那里
Stand right there.
你满头大汗
You look like you're sweating.
因为天热
Well, it's hot.
或者是你在逃跑
Or you've been running.
我为什么要跑
Why would I be running?
因为你们是一伙的
Because you're a part of it.
什么一伙
Part of what?
-是我在问问题  -快跑
- I'll ask the questions. - Go! Run!
九号码头  他们向南跑了
Pier Nine, Pier Nine, runners heading south!
快点  跑
Move it! Go!
不介意的话  我可以在这里等你
I can wait for you here, if you want.
你的朋友
Friends of yours?
什么
What?
别装了
You heard me.
等等  没有
Wait, no... Uh...
我不认识这里的任何人
I don't know anybody here.
我是游客
I'm a tourist.
游客不会跑
Tourists don't run.
可我没跑
But I'm not running.
你说对了
You got that right.
注：KX系列帝国安保机器人(KX-series security droid)，出自《侠盗一号》
现在跑来不及了
That window is shut.
我只是去商店
I'm just going to the store.
就在那里
It's right there.
请你冷静  先生
You need to calm down, sir.
机器人  请过来协助
Droid assistance, please.
什么  等等  这是什么  不  这太离谱了
Uh... What? Wait. What is he... No, this is crazy.
帮我盯住这个家伙
Hang onto this one for me.
我去检查庇护所
I wanna check the shelter.
他说钉
He said hang?
不  不是
No, no, no. No.
不  你误会了
No, you misunderstand.
不  他的意思是看住
No, he... he meant watch.
-钉  -不  他的意思是看住
- Hang? - No, no, he means watch.
钉住
Hang.
告诉他
Tell him!
告诉他  你的意思是看住
Tell him you mean watch!
罪名
Charges?
在犯罪现场游荡
Loitering at a crime scene.
遛马西夫犬不牵绳
Walking an unleashed massif.
不清理动物粪便
Animal fouling.
四个月
Four months.
下一个
Next.
基夫·格戈
Keef Girgo?
Keef Girgo!
在
Here.
-名字  -基夫·格戈
- Name? - Hey, uh, Keef Girgo.
-罪名  -制造混乱
- Charges? - Civil Disruption.
-反帝国言论  -不
- Anti-Imperial speech. - No. No.
逃离反帝活动现场
Fleeing the scene of anti-Imperial activity.
企图损坏帝国财产
Attempted damage...
-不好意思  这是个误会  -别多嘴
- I... I'm sorry, there's something wrong. - I wouldn't.
你没算上反抗判决  指控已经够多了
You've got enough trouble without a Resisting Judgement charge.
我只是个游客
I'm just a tourist.
那就不好意思了
Oh, apologies all around then.
本来只是六个月刑期
This used to be a six-month sentence.
六年
Six years.
-六年  -六年
- Six years? - Six years?
-不  等等  -带走
- No, no, wait! - Take him.
-规则变了  -把他带走
- Change of guidelines. - Take him away.
-我什么都没做  -去跟皇帝说吧
- I didn't do anything! Hey! - Take it up with the Emperor.
等等  我只是个游客
Wait. I'm just a tourist!
-下一个  -等等
- Next. - Wait!